			Hibernate Object States/Persistence Life Cycle


	Transient State-->Persitent State-->
	
	By default all the object are transient and the moment that object is saved it becomes persistent.
	And when the object is inthe persistent state at that point of time wahtever changes we make with the object the same reflects in the database as well.



next →← prev
Hibernate Second Level Cache
Hibernate second level cache uses a common cache for all the session object of a session factory.
 It is useful if you have multiple session objects from a session factory.

SessionFactory holds the second level cache data. It is global for all the session objects and not enabled by default.

Different vendors have provided the implementation of Second Level Cache.


EH Cache
OS Cache
Swarm Cache
JBoss Cache
Each implementation provides different cache usage functionality. There are four ways to use second level cache.

read-only: caching will work for read only operation.
nonstrict-read-write: caching will work for read and write but one at a time.
read-write: caching will work for read and write, can be used simultaneously.
transactional: caching will work for transaction.